[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
In this module we're going to talk about the specific boosting algorithm called
في هذه الوحدة، سنقوم بالحديث عن خوارزمية تعزيز محددة تسمى
AdaBoost.
AdaBoost.
AdaBoost is one of the early machine learning algorithms for boosting.
AdaBoost هي واحدة من أوائل خوارزميات التعلم الآلي لتعزيزه.
It's extremely useful.
وهي مفيدة للغاية.
It's very simple to implement.
وبسيطة للغاية في تنفيذها.
And it's quite effective.
وكذلك فعالة جدًا.
There are others.
وهناك آخرون.
I'll mention another interesting one towards the end of the module but
سأذكر واحدة أخرى مثيرة للاهتمام في نهاية الوحدة ولكن
let's start with AdaBoost.
دعونا نبدأ مع AdaBoost.
This is the famous AdaBoost algorithm,
هذه هي خوارزمية AdaBoost الشهيرة،
which was created by Freund and Schapire in 1999, amazing useful algorithm.
والتي أنشئت بواسطة فرويند وشابيري في عام 1999، وهي خوارزمية مدهشة ومفيدة.
So you start by seeing every data point the same way.
لذا يمكنك البدء برؤية كل نقطة بيانات بنفس الطريقة.
You don't know which ones are hard, which ones are easy.
إذًا أنت لا تعرف أيها الأصعب، وأيها الأسهل.
They all have the same weight.
فجميعها لها نفس الوزن.
And so you can start with them all weight, we'll start with them with weight 1 over
لذا حتى تتمكن من البدء في العمل عليها، سوف نبدأ معها بوزن 1 على
N, because it makes everything kind of work out a little better.
N، لأن ذلك يجعل كل شيء يعمل بشكلٍ أفضل قليلًا نوعًا ما.
And we'll talk about why in a few slides, but
وسوف نتحدث عن السبب بعد بضع شرائح، ولكن
we start to all data points having the same what's called uniform weight.
نبدأ مع كافة نقاط البيانات لها نفس ما يسمى بالوزن الموحد.
So in this case alpha i is one over n.
لذا في هذه الحالة α تساوي واحدًا على n.
And then for each iteration of AdaBoost, as you go to learn the first
ثم لكل تكرار من AdaBoost، بينما تتابع، ستكتشف أول
decision stamp or the first simple classifier or the first weight classifier,
ختم قرار أو أول مصنف بسيط أو مصنف الوزن الأول،
the second one, or the third one all the way to capital T.
والمصنف الثاني، أو الثالث حتى الوصول إلى T.
What we do is we learn ft on weighted data is alpha i.
ما نقوم به هو أننا نحدد ft على البيانات المرجحة α i.
So that's the data, is the weights start with 1 over N but
إذًا هذه هي البيانات، هي الأوزان التي تبدأ مع 1 على N ولكن
they get different over time.
تصبح مختلفة على مر الزمن.
Then we compute the coefficient w hat t for
ثم نحسب المعامل w hat t
this new classify ft that we learned.
لهذا التصنيف الجديد ft الذي حددناه.
And then we recompute the weights alpha i.
وبعد ذلك يمكننا إعادة حساب الأوزان α i.
And we keep going, and finally once we're done we say that the prediction y hat is
ثم نستمر في العمل، وأخيرً بمجرد الانتهاء نقول إن التنبؤ y hat
the sign of the weighted combination of f1, f2, f3,
هو علامة الجمع المرجح لـ f1 وf2 وf3
f4 weighted by these coefficients that we learn from later.
وf4 مرجحة بهذه المعاملات التي تعلمناها مما سبق.
So there are two fundamental problems we need to address
لذلك هناك اثنان من المسائل الأساسية التي نكون بحاجة إلى معالجتها
when we're thinking about AdaBoost.
عندما نفكر في AdaBoost.
One is, how do you compute the coefficient w hat t,
واحدة هي كيف يمكنك حساب المعامل w hat t،
let's call that problem 1 in our module for today.
دعونا ندعو تلك المسألة 1 في وحدتنا اليوم.
So problem 1 is how much do I trust ftF in this case?
وبالتالي فإن المسألة 1 هي ما مدى ثقتي في ftF في هذه الحالة؟
So if I trust ft a lot, I should give it a very high weight.
لذا إن وثقت في ft كثيرًا، ينبغي أن أعطى وزنًا عاليًا جدًا.
If I trust ft very little,
وإذا وثقت ft بشكل قليل جدًا،
I should give it a very low weight, or a very low coefficient, I should say.
ينبغي إعطاء وزن منخفض جدًا، أو معامل منخفض جدًا، كما يجب القول.
And then problem 2 is how do you recompute this weight on the data points?
ثم هناك المسألة 2 حول كيف يمكنك إعادة حساب هذا الوزن في نقاط البيانات؟
Let's call that problem 2.
لنطلق على هذا المسألة 2.
And so, problem 2 here is how
وهكذا، تكون المسألة 2 هنا هي
do we weigh mistakes more?
كيف نرجح الأخطاء بشكل أكبر؟
So we want to increase the weights of mistakes.
حسنًا نحن نرغب في زيادة ترجيحات الأخطاء.
So in the main part of this module, we're going to talk about how do
وبالتالي في الجزء الرئيسي من هذه الوحدة، سنتحدث بشأن كيفية
you compute w hat t and how we can update alpha i's, and
حسابك لقيمة w hat t وكيف يمكننا تحديث قيم α i
it's going to be pretty simple, relatively intuitive, extremely useful.
وسيكون الأمر بسيطًا للغاية وبديهي بشكل نسبي ومفيدًا جدًا.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]